Sofia Fong

sofia.fong5@hotmail.com 206-446-3283 Seattle, WA https://www.linkedin.com/in/sofia-fong/ sofong5.github.io

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Highly-killed and enthusiastic software engineering professional with experience in backend and fullstack projects. Industry expertise in telecommunications, social media, and gaming. Proven track-record of delivering effective solutions to address complex problems to enhance everyday life.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Python, C, C++, C#, Unity, Kotlin, HTML/CSS, SQL, MongoDB, Hive, Pytorch, Javascript

EXPERIENCE

Meta, Seattle, WA September 2022 - Present

Software Engineer - Bootcamper

Brex, Remote (VC-Backed, 1.21B Capital, 1150 Employees) September 2021 - December 2021

Software Engineer Intern - Communications

Planned, built, and administered software focused on financial and card services.

- Designed and implemented a new service along with a new interface to send ad-hoc notifications to target users using Kotlin and Retool.
- Created new endpoints in existing API to provide the necessary functionally to support the new service using Elixir and Typescript.

Facebook, Remote January 2021 - April 2021

Software Engineer Intern - Pytorch at Scale

Collaborated on a team of 100+ software engineers to build utility servers with custom application designed to streamline Facebook features.

- Redesigned and enhanced the benchmarking suite for the collective communications library Gloo used to train large ML models distributed across thousands of GPUs
- Created a simplified version of Facebook's Ads model using Pytorch to validate the efficiency of Gloo within a simulated environment

University of Waterloo, Waterloo, ON

Software Developer - Networking and Game Design

Worked effectively as a part of a team of 6 programmers to architect and build a cross platform online megagame that can scale to thousands of users using C#, Godot, and .NET

Designed and implemented front-end, back-end, and UI game features using C# and Godot

Wish/ContextLogic, San Francisco, CA (raised 1.1B) September 2019 - December 2019 Software Engineer Intern - Merchant Payments

Worked with a team of developers, project managers, and designers to maintain and enhance the front and back end of the merchant portal

- Developed and implemented new schema, API endpoints, and front end components to display sales metrics for merchants using MongoDB, Hive, Airflow, Python, and React
- Created a dashboard displaying daily KPIs used to make key business decisions that impact thousands of merchants using Python, Hive, TreasureData, Prometheus, and Grafana

EDUCATION AND PROFESSIONAL DEVELOPMENT

Bachelor of Computer Science (BCS) - University of Waterloo

The Submarine - Designed and developed a point and click escape room game using C# and Unity **UWEnergyHacks Hackathon** - Conceptualized an app to encourage sustainable living using Figma **Cooking Club Executive** - Worked with a team of 20 executives to coordinate events for students